来吧你就
Oh, come on, you...
我来帮你吧
Can I gave you a hand?
如果我需要帮忙  我就张口了
If I needed a hand, I'd ask for it --
非常感谢
thank you very much.
-给您  女士  -谢谢
- There you go, miss. - Thanks.
玛丽恩  你好吗
Marion. How's it going?
那么回事吧  脑子还好使
Could be worse. Brain's still working.
今天来点五香熏牛肉吗
Is it a pastrami day?
-要  只要一斤一两  -好的
- Yeah. Uh, one and a quarter pounds. - You got it.
不是一斤四两  你上次称多了
Not a pound and a half, you overshot last time.
对不起
Sorry 'bout that.
这是什么
What do we have here?
特干威斯康辛切达奶酪
Extra-sharp Wisconsin cheddar.
特干
"Extra-sharp," Hmm?
可算了吧  威斯康辛
You can keep it, Wisconsin.
人人影视
原创翻译  双语字幕
字幕组招新中
请访问 yysub.net
我之前来的时候不是这样的
It wasn't like this when I came before.
翻译    Margaery  Eunice
翻译    杏仁斯嘉丽  吃冰棒
翻译    子V
需要帮忙吗
Need some help?
不用
I'm fine!
校对    杏仁斯嘉丽   Eunice
时间轴    今   大葱
确定不需要推一下吗
Are you sure you don't want a push?
确定
I'm sure.
后期    8T
我叫咬咬  你见过我吗  请打402-432-9288
小咬咬怎么了
What happened to poor Nippy?
总监    喃喃
都怪我
It was my fault.
我开车的时候开着车窗
I was driving with the windows open,
当时还没下雪
you know, before all this hit.
我也不知道  什么东西吸引了他
And -- I don't know -- something got into him.
他看见小猫之类的了  跳了出去
He saw a cat or something -- but he jumped.
不是吧
Oh, no.
我立刻停车
I pulled right over,
大喊着"咬咬"
screaming my head off, "Nippyyyy!"
但是  他跑了
But...he was gone.
太可怕了
Oh, that's terrible.
希望你能找到他
I hope you find him.
拜托帮忙留意一下
If you could keep an eye out.
没问题  肯定的
Yeah, I will. Sure.
我就在这住  在克莱门汀街
I-I live right over here on -- on Clementine.
我就走这条路
This is my route.
等我把这破玩意开起来的
When I can get this thing going.
还是稍微推一下吧
Maybe just a little push.
如果你不介意的话
Well, if you're sure you don't mind.
乐意帮忙
Nah. I'm happy to help.
好了  挂到空挡上
Okay. Throw it in neutral.
一  二  三
And one, two, three.
好了
There you go.
抱歉添麻烦了
Sorry for the trouble.
挂回行驶挡  不用客气
Put it back in drive. Not at all.
-祝你开心  -你也是
- Have a nice day. - Yeah, you too.
希望你能找到咬咬
Hope you find Nippy.
谢谢
Thank you.
什么鬼
What in the world?
还行吗  玛丽恩
How ya doing, Marion?
-好极了  -那就好
- Great. - Ah, good.
-你可以吧  -没问题
- Are you okay? - Oh, yeah.
绝命律师
第六季第十集
阿尔布开克同位素棒球队
好了  好了
Okay, okay, okay.
其实  这是我的拿手好菜
Actually, it's my favorite meal to cook.
-我喜欢  -我的秘诀就是...
- I like it. - And I think my secret is --
妈
Ma?
在厨房  杰夫
In the kitchen, Jeffie!
我有个秘诀
I have a little trick.
我敢肯定跟我家一个做法
I bet it's the same we do in my family.
-加个蛋  -我就知道
- An egg. - I knew it.
要搅拌均匀
And you really work it in.
一定要用手抓
I mean, you got to use your hands.
就是这么回事
You are speaking my language.
-你下厨吗  -就几个家常菜  不做什么大餐
- Do you cook? - Just a few favorites, nothing fancy.
简单最好了  何必麻烦呢
Yeah, simple's best. I mean, why fuss?
杰夫  这位是塔卡维奇先生
Jeffie, this is Mr. Takavic.
我父亲才叫塔卡维奇先生呢
Oh, please, Mr. Takavic was my father.
叫我吉恩
Call me "Gene."
别担心  孩子  他不是什么斧子杀手
Don't worry, hon, he's not an ax murderer.
他要是想砍了我  他早就动手了
If he was gonna chop me to bits he'd have done it already.
对吧  吉恩
Right, Gene?
别在那傻站着了  快一起坐下
Well, don't just stand there like a bump on a log, join us.
有时候他见到生人有点紧张
Sometimes he gets a little nervous around new people.
-妈  -本来嘛
- Ma. - Well, you do.
快点
Now come on.
拿个杯子坐下
Grab a glass and sit down.
给他讲讲我们怎么认识的  吉恩
Tell him how we met, Gene.
好的
Oh, yeah.
当时我正在找咬咬
Uh, well, I was looking for Nippy --
对  他的狗  小可怜
Yeah. His dog, poor thing.
他跑丢了
Well, he ran away.
吉恩当时正在贴寻狗启事
And Gene here was putting up posters.
你母亲刚好从汉森超市回来
And your mom was on her way back from Hansen's.
我的轮子卡在雪里了
And my wheels got stuck in the snow.
然后助力车整个坏掉了
Well, that was before the whole thing conked out.
是的  但是吉恩今天就是大救星
Yeah, but Gene here saved the day.
他还用强力胶带修好了我的破车
He even fixed my dumb scooter -- with duct tape!
-敬吉恩  -别客气
- To Gene. - Come on.
来吧
Yeah.
你母亲说你是出租车司机
So your mom tells me you're a cab driver?
你载过什么名人吗
Have you ever driven anyone famous?
那是当然
Oh, he sure did.
给他讲讲  杰夫
Tell him, Jeffie.
萨米·海格
Sammy Hagar.
不会吧  "红色摇滚乐手"
No! The Red Rocker?!
我很喜欢他
Hey, I love him.
♪ 我不能超速55迈 ♪
♪ I can't drive 55 ♪
就是这首
That's it!
他人怎么样  大方吗
What was he like? Big tipper?
还行
I guess.
这样  你消停坐着
You know what? You stay comfy.
我来把这道美味端上来
I will rescue this beautiful creation.
看看
Look at that.
来啦
Ta-da!
吉恩跟我们一起吃晚饭
Gene's staying for dinner.
哥们  搞什么
Dude, what the fuck?!
我知道感觉很怪
I know it's awkward, right?
但是你还不用管我叫爸爸
But you don't have to call me "Dad" yet.
我不知道你想要什么  但是我只要
I dunno what this is about -- but all I have to do
打一通电话  索尔·古德曼就拜拜了
is pick up the phone and it's bye-bye, Saul Goodman.
是  但你这不是还没打电话呢吗
Yeah, but you haven't picked up the phone yet, have you?
也没打我一顿抢我钱
Or tried to strong-arm me for cash.
你猜怎么着  我知道为什么
And guess what? I know why.
因为奖金  勒索
Because reward money, blackmail --
都勾不起你的兴趣
that's not gonna tickle your pickle.
我知道你真正想要的是什么
I know what you really want.
是吗  要什么
Oh, yeah? What's that?
你想入局
You want in the game.
局  什么  什么局
"The game"? W-What -- What game?
局
The game.
你这辈子都在看着的
The one you've been watching your entire life.
脸趴在玻璃上鼻子都压扁了
You got your nose pressed up against the glass,
认真看大哥哥们玩
peerin' in while the big boys play.
好好说话
Man, speak English.
你到底说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
入局
The game.
就在那
It's right there --
你看得见  却摸不着
you can see it, but you can't touch it.
车子  衣服  钞票
The cars, the clothes, the cash.
女人
The ladies.
左右逢源  黑白通吃
It's about knowing all the angles, you know,
孤注一掷  大赚一笔
putting it all on the line and winning big.
可是你在这  杰夫
But here you are, Jeffie.
和废物们一起站在局外
Standing outside with the suckers.
想还清出租车的贷款  努力工作付账单
Tryin' to pay off that cab, sweatin' the bills,
年纪越来越大
gettin' older.
离得那么近  可是偏偏无法参加
It's so close, but, damn it, you just can't get in.
直到现在
Until now.
我能让你梦想成真
I can make it happen.
你
You?
索尔·古德曼
Saul Goodman.
这样吧
So, here's the deal.
我带你看看我们的局
I will show you the game.
然后我们就一拍两散
And then we're done.
...两天
...two days.
报警人认为疑犯是有暴力史的姐夫
Caller thinks it's brother-in-law with history of violence.
收到
10-4.
噪音投诉  约有50名青少年
Noise complaint. 50 or so teens.
父母可能出城了
Parents possibly out of town.
邻居说这不是第一次了
Neighbors say this is not the first time.
你的位置
10-20?
峰景路37882号
37882 Crestview.
我马上过去
Headed that way.
有未成年人失踪  白人男性
Missing juvenile. Caucasian male.
身高188厘米  体重108公斤
6'2", 240 pounds.
最后一次出现是在
Last seen at gas station
凯瑞伍德路和韦斯顿路交界处的加油站
on Kerrywood and Western.
父母报警了吗
Parents called?
联系上他母亲了  预计20分钟后到
Got ahold of Mom. ETA is 20 minutes.
到达现场
10-23.
晚安  女士们
G'night, ladies.
-再见  吉恩  -再见
- See ya, Gene. - Bye.
好
Yeah.
安保
棉白杨商场
北区安保
出什么问题了吗
There a problem?
没有  我就是来道谢
No, I -- I just came to say thanks.
我叫吉恩
Um, I'm Gene.
辛纳邦的店员
From Cinnabon.
我之前晕倒了
Uh, you called the EMTs for me
你帮我叫了急救人员
when I...fainted.
对  我记得你
Yeah. I remember you.
"找个律师"
"Get a lawyer!"
尼克  我好像闻到肉桂卷的香味了
Nick! Do I detect Cinnabons?
没错
Yeah!
那你还不快让他进来
Well, Christ almighty, get him in here.
律师那事我很抱歉
I'm sorry about the lawyer thing.
不知怎的脱口而出
Just slipped out.
这是个自由的国家
It's a free country.
你好  我是吉恩·塔卡维奇
Hi. Uh, Gene Takavic.
吉恩你好  我是弗兰克  他是尼克
Hey, Gene. I'm Frank. This is Nick.
这位尼克帮助过我
Yeah. Nick here, um, did me a solid,
所以
so, uh...
那个
Well...
你们尽情吃吧
Please -- enjoy yourselves.
你人真好
Well, God bless ya.
已经9点45了  尼克  你想带走吃吗
Well 9:45. Nick, you wanna grab yours to-go?
-好啊  -他得去巡逻
- Sure. - Yeah. He's gotta check the lot.
好
Yeah.
谢了
Thanks.
你想坐下休息会吗
You want to take a load off?
你要是想  可以自己去倒杯咖啡
Grab yourself a cup of coffee if you'd like.
-好啊  -好不
- Yeah. - Yeah?
好的
Oh. Okay.
我真不该吃这个的
I should not be doing this.
帮我个忙
Hey, do me a favor,
要是你哪天遇到我老婆  千万别告诉她
if you were ever to cross paths with my wife, shh.
我保证不说
Scout's honor.
天啊
Oh, man.
我好久没吃过了
I haven't had one of these in forever.
我得控制腰围
Watching my waistline.
-但偶尔吃一个  -也无妨  对吧
- Yeah, but every now and then-- - No harm, right?
你昨晚看球赛了吗
So, did you catch the game last night?
球赛
The game?
那帮废物怎么回事啊
What the hell is wrong with those guys?
我都不知道从何吐槽起
I can't even talk about it.
我本来以为今年真能有好成绩的
Really thought this was the year.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
得州队根本不入流
You know, Texas wasn't even ranked.
就是啊
I know.
用的什么破战术
Play-calling was crazy.
糟透了
The worst.
三次进攻才推进了半米
Three downs to make a foot and a half?
能有多难啊
How hard can it be?
马丁内斯打的那个鬼样  怎么可能赢
Well, you can't win when Martinez plays like that.
马丁内斯
Martinez.
这哥们怎么回事啊
I mean, what's up with him?
你说是不是有点不对劲
You think something's off?
有可能
Maybe.
下周对俄克拉荷马州队
Next week, Oklahoma State.
-俄克佬  -什么
- The Okies. - Huh?
我们以前是这么喊他们的
Uh, that's what we called them.
你有没有开过那条巡礼路线
You ever done the drive?
-托皮卡  威奇托...  -真好
- Topeka, Wichita... - Nice.
那说明你没开过
Well, then you haven't done it.
哪也比不过纪念球场
Can't beat Memorial.
太对了
Damn straight.
你最喜欢什么
What do you love most?
太难选了
Now, that's a tough one.
你觉得威登回到主场能恢复状态吗
You think Weedon'll come through on his home turf?
-嗯  -怎么可能
- Yeah. - No way!
-他手指都受伤了  -手指确实能影响战局
- With that thumb? - Thumb's a dealbreaker.
我跟你说
I'll tell you something.
就是美洲狮头盔把他手指弄折了
The Cougar helmet was the thumb-breaker.
太好吃了
Delicious.
我该回去了
Welp, I should probably be heading back.
太感谢啦
Well, thanks again.
应该的
Oh, it's the least I could do.
再见
Have a good one.
欢迎你随时再来
Come back anytime.
-晚安  吉恩  -晚安  克丽丝塔
- Have a good night, Gene. - Goodnight, Krista.
-晚安  -晚安
- Goodnight. - Goodnight.
弗兰克
Frank?
吉恩  吉恩  人形肉桂卷机
Gene, Gene, the Cinnabon machine.
你在走廊我就闻到了
I could smell ya coming up the hallway.
经常有人这么说
Oh, I get that all the time.
开吃吧
Here you go, guys.
我能不能...
Hey, can I --
吉恩  你都不用问啦  自己倒咖啡吧
Hey, Gene, don't even ask. Grab a coffee.
昨晚那场球赛太精彩了
That was one hell of a game, huh?
中场休息时你有什么想法
What were you thinking at halftime?
我当时在想
Well, uh, I was thinking,
"这场比赛
"Hey, this could, uh --
估计是持久战"
this could be a long one."
你知道我今天不会怨谁吗
And I tell you, you know who I'm not bitching about today?
-佩利尼  -佩利尼  那个教练
- Pelini. Nah. - Pelini. That's -- Yeah, the coach.
你知道我的  每次输球我第一个骂他
You know me. I go at him when things are bad,
但他表现好的时候  我也不吝赞美
but when he does something good, I'm all about it.
-晚安  吉恩  -晚安
- Goodnight, Gene. - Goodnight!
收他入队是有原因的
They got him in there for a reason.
先生们
Gentlemen!
我宝刀未老
I still got it.
需要帮忙吗  先生
Can I help you, sir?
需要
Oh, yeah.
还是不用了  谢谢
Uh, no thanks.
我就随便看看
I'm just browsing.
好的
Okay. Yeah.
四  五  六
4, 5, 6,
七  八  九
7, 8, 9...
十四
...14...
十五  十七  十八
...15, 17, 18.
六  七  八  九  十
6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
二
2...
十一  十二  十三
11, 12, 13,
十四  十五
14, 15.
好了
Alright. Aaand...
十七步
17 feet.
就是这里
Right here.
用缎带围起来
Ribbon it off.
快点
Come on.
全围起来
All the way, guys.
好了
Okay.
喂喂  一二  一二
Check, check, one, two. One, two.
好了  动起来吧
Alright, let's move.
起点就在那
Starting position. Right down there.
准备好了吗
Alright, we ready?
拿上你的包
And grab your bag!
开始
And go!
就这样  快跑
That's it! Move! Move!
快快快
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
一  阿玛尼西装拿了跑
One! Armani suits and run!
二  乔丹球鞋归你有
Two! Air Jordan shoes for you!
三  亚麻衬衣免费拿
Three! Linen shirts for free!
四  羊绒毛衣出门走
Four! Cashmere sweaters out the door!
五  巴塔哥尼亚户外装
Five! Patagonias to survive!
六  时髦运动服随意搭
Six! Swanky sweatsuits in the mix!
-停  -怎么了
- Halt! - Ohh. What?
太多了
Too many.
你得精准点儿
You gotta be precise.
每样拿三件
Just three of each.
为什么
Why?
我为什么要像个傻子一样跑来跑去
And why do I gotta run around like an asshole?
我不是告诉你了吗
I already told you.
三分钟
Three minutes.
明白吗  我们只有三分钟
Got it? That's our window.
为什么只有三分钟
Yeah, but why three minutes?
因为过了三分钟保安就会在监控里看见你
Because at three minutes, that's when security sees you
警察就会把你扔进监狱  明白吗
on the cameras and the cops haul your ass to jail, alright?
-来吧  -等等  还有监控
- So let's go. - Wait -- there's cameras?
当然有监控
Sure, there's cameras!
每72小时就洗一遍录像带
They erase the tapes every 72 hours.
所以你每样只能拿三件
So that's why you only take three of each.
只拿值钱的
And only the pricey stuff.
等商场第二天早上开门
When the store opens the next morning,
他们都不知道自己被洗劫了
they won't even know they were robbed.
等他们盘点库存的时候  哗啦啦变
By the time they do inventory, abracadabra!
录像带上就没有杰夫了
No more Jeffie on the tape, right?
三件  三分钟
So, three items, three minutes.
很容易
It's easy.
开始
Let's go.
每样几件
How many of each?
三件
Three.
人心不足蛇吞象
Pigs get fat, hogs get slaughtered.
我不知道
I dunno...
你不知道什么
What don't you know?
整个计划太疯狂了
It's just, this whole thing -- it seems crazy.
太棘手你做不来吗
Is this too hot for you?
你要是这么想就直说吧
You know, just say so.
你知道吗  去他的
You know what? Screw it.
"疯狂"
"Crazy"?
我告诉你什么叫疯狂
I'll tell you what's crazy.
有个50岁的高中化学老师
Fifty-year-old high school chemistry teacher
来我办公室
comes into my office.
这家伙穷光蛋一个  付不起贷款
The guy is so broke, he can't pay his own mortgage.
一年后  他有了一辆大众车那么大一堆现金
One year later, he's got a pile of cash as big as a Volkswagen.
这才叫疯狂
That's crazy.
我来
I'll do it.
你觉得可以
This sounds good to you?
我觉得能行
I think it'll work.
瞧瞧你
Well, look at you.
很年轻
You're young.
估计跑得快
You're probably, uh, fast on the feet, huh?
好吧  我没说我不干
Okay, I-I didn't say I wouldn't do it.
我只是有点关于后勤的问题
I just had some questions about, like, logistics.
你到底干不干
Are you in or out?
干
In.
好
Okay.
从一开始
Back to one.
喂喂  一二  一二
Check, test, one, two, one, two.
好了  各就各位  预备  跑
Okay, and ready, set, action!
快跑
Move! Move! Move!
脚步快点  快快快
Pick up the pace! Go! Go! Go!
一  阿玛尼西装拿了跑
One! Armani suits and run!
二  乔丹球鞋归你有
Two! Air Jordan shoes for you!
三  亚麻衬衣免费拿
Three! Linen shirts for free!
四  羊绒毛衣出门走
Four! Cashmere sweaters out the door!
五  巴塔哥尼亚户外装
Five! Patagonias to survive!
六  时髦运动服随意搭
Six! Swanky sweatsuits in the mix!
快跑快跑快跑
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
-芭芭拉  -怎么了
- Barbara? - Yes?
让维修部给这里做下抛光
Let's ask maintenance to give this area a polish.
好  我这就打电话
Got it, I'll call now.
谢谢
Thanks.
好了  晚安
Okay, then. Have a good night.
晚安
You too.
不好意思  女士
Excuse me, ma'am?
有货物送到了
There's a delivery.
货物
A delivery?
不
No.
不行
No, no.
停
Stop.
不能把它留在我的装卸口
You are not leaving that thing on my loading dock.
不行
No way.
棉白杨大道1412号
Fourteen twelve Cottonwood Drive...
D装卸口
Dock -- Dock D.
给我看看
Let me see.
二冲程发动机喷雾泵
Two-stroke engine sprayer pumps?
我们是百货商场
This is a department store.
你觉得我们用得上喷雾泵吗
Does it look like we use sprayer pumps here?
我们用不上
Well, we don't.
他们给我的就是这个地址  女士
I was given this address, ma'am.
我要跟你的上级通话
I need to talk to your supervisor.
找到了  你待着别动
Got it. You stay right here.
调度中心  史蒂夫
Dispatch. Steve.
我是凯茜·德驰
Yes -- this is Kathy Deutsch,
我是奥马哈市一家兰开斯特百货的经理
I'm the manager of a Lancaster's in Omaha.
你们送来了一样
And you guys just delivered something
-我们没订的东西  -是吗
- that we did not order. - Really?
你的员工把一个巨大的木箱送到我的装卸口
Your guy brought a giant wooden crate onto my loading dock,
好像是一个喷雾泵之类的
seems to be some kind of spraying system.
发票编号是1968AE35
The invoice number is 1-9-6-8-AE35.
好  稍等一下我捋捋
Okay, just, uh, give me a second to catch up here.
喷雾泵
Uh... Uh, sprayer pump.
我记得
Yeah, I think I got it.
奥马哈  对吗
Omaha, right?
对  但我们是百货公司
Yes, but I run a department store.
我们不卖喷雾泵
We don't sell anything like that.
这个错误你得解决
Clearly this is a mistake you need to fix.
天啊  真抱歉  女士
Oh, my God. I'm so sorry, ma'am.
我的老板会...
My boss is gonna just...
这下可好
Ah, great.
瑞奇的时间都排满了
Ricky's booked solid.
瑞奇
Ricky?
他是司机
He's the driver.
瑞奇把箱子搬回卡车上就行了
Well, Ricky's just gonna have to put the box back on the truck.
但是有点问题
Uh, little problem with that.
载货空间
Cargo space.
他一小时后要在机场接货
He's got a pickup at the airport in an hour.
也很麻烦
It's a messy one, too.
408公斤西班牙鲭鱼
It's, uh, nine hundred pounds of Spanish mackerel.
好吧  很遗憾  但这不是我的问题
Okay. I'm sorry, but that's not my problem.
确实  我知道  就是
No, I know. It's just -- Wow.
要是他迟到了  鱼就臭了[就坏事了]
I mean, if he's late, that's gonna stink.
是双关
Pun intended.
吉恩  还好吗
Gene? Everything okay?
嗯  我就是在处理紧急情况
Yep. Oh, I'm just, uh, putting out fires.
送货问题
It's a delivery issue.
-别担心  -好
- Don't worry. - Okay.
我能处理
I got it.
抱歉
Sorry.
-你还在听吗  -在
- You still there? - Yes.
关于你的鱼问题  我不知道该说些什么
Look, I don't know what to tell you about your fish issue,
只不过我不能让这么大个箱子...
it's just I can't have a huge box just --
我理解
I-I understand.
我们...
It's just -- I mean, we both have people
都只是个打工的  对吗
we have to answer to, right?
我有个主意
Hey, I've got an idea.
我还有辆车
Um, I've got an extra truck.
我可以亲自开过来
I could drive over there myself.
那好  你多久能到
Great. How long till you get here?
我现在还在厄本代尔
Well, I'm just over in Urbandale.
所以  如果我现在出发  四个小时能到
Um, so, if I leave right now, be there in four hours.
四个小时  不行
Four hours? No.
没事  没事  没关系  这点车程没什么
No, no, it's fine. I don't mind the drive.
我找几首歌路上听  就像以前一样
I'll crank the tunes, it'll be like old times.
我是指我等不了那么久
I mean, no, I can't wait around that long.
我们要打烊了
We're closing for the night here.
要不这么着
How's this?
什么
Yeah?
如果你能保证...
If you promise me that...
瑞奇明早十点之前能回来...
Ricky will get back here by 10:00 a.m. tomorrow...
我可以让箱子在这存放一晚
I'll hold the box overnight.
你愿意通融吗
You would do that?
天啊  你真是我的大恩人
Oh, my God. You're a lifesaver.
你叫什么来着
What's your name again?
-凯茜  -凯茜
- Kathy. - Kathy.
一言为定  我的人早上十点一定准时到
Yeah, my guy'll be there, 10:00 a.m. on the dot.
带上鲜花聊表心意
With flowers.
花就不必了
Well, f-flowers won't be necessary...
不过还是谢谢你的心意
but thanks for the thought.
不  该说谢谢的是我
No, thank you.
晚安  女士们
G'night, ladies.
-晚安  -晚安  吉恩
- 'Night. - Good night, Gene.
-先生们好  -你好  吉恩
- Gentlemen. - Hey, Gene.
嗨  吉恩
Heya, Gene.
我该去巡逻了
Well, better hit it.
祝莉兹拼字比赛取得好成绩
Good luck to Lizzie on that spelling bee.
她有点紧张
She's a little nervous.
没事  她肯定能赢
Nah, she's gonna be great.
收割者队强势回归了
Hey, Huskers are back.
我的尖叫声可能都一路传到林肯市去了
Probably heard me screaming all the way in Lincoln.
我嗓子都喊哑了
I was hoarse.
还有  马丁内斯
Uh, and Martinez -- ahh.
狂掠484码  那可破了新人记录
484 yards? That's a freshman record!
你知道吗
You know what?
我很喜欢那小子
I love that kid.
要是他和金尼能保持住
Hey, if he and Kinnie keep it up,
我觉得他们还有机会
I think they still got a shot.
托你吉言
Your lips to God's ears.
好了
Okay.
你好  大美人
Hello, gorgeous.
行动
一  阿玛尼西装拿了跑
One, Armani suits and run.
阿玛尼  阿玛尼  阿玛尼
Armani, Armani, Armani.
阿玛尼
Armani.
Armani?
阿玛尼
Armani.
二  乔丹球鞋归你有
Two, Air Jordan shoes for you.
好了
Alright.
三  亚麻衬衣免费拿
Three, linen shirts for free.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
四  羊绒毛衣出门走
Four, cashmere sweaters out the door.
这个不行  好  好  好
No. Yes, yes, yes.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
五  巴塔哥尼亚户外装
Five, Patagonias to survive.
多了六千个座位
6,000 more seats.
多了六千个球迷
6,000 more fans.
不好说  还有那些豪华套房
I don't know. All those luxury suites?
现在要开始存钱了
Start saving now.
你看佩利尼的采访了吗
You see that interview with Pelini?
那家伙现在干劲十足
The guy's feeling his oats.
他尝到赢球的滋味了
He can taste it now.
你觉得他能走出奥斯本的阴影吗
You think he'll ever get outta Osborne's shadow?
奥斯本  职业传奇
Osborne -- what a career.
名人堂成员  还是国会议员
I mean, a hall of famer and a congressman?
难以置信
Unbelievable.
七  天赐华服披我身
Seven, spendy dresses sent from heaven.
九五年冠军队
'95 team?
明星阵容
What a line up.
那个I阵型
I mean, the "I formation."
要我说
Well, I'll tell ya,
佩利尼就该向他学着点
Pelini could have taken a page outta that book.
九  昂贵内衣属于我
Nine, pricey lingerie is mine.
十  男士小牛皮公文包
Ten, calfskin briefcases for men.
没有可比性  朋友
Apples and oranges, my friend.
毕竟奥斯本手下有伟大的汤米·弗雷泽
Oh, come on. Osborne had the great Tommie Frazier.
弗雷泽
Frazier!
-对了  跟我一起念  -弗雷泽  没错  没错
- Yeah, say it with me. - Frazier. Yeah, sure, sure.
十二  奢华高跟鞋跟我走
Twelve, luxury pumps to un-shelve.
那场44比21赢了水牛队的比赛
How about that 44-21 win against the Buffs?
我当时激动坏了
Be still my heart.
从76码外传给雷吉·鲍尔
Seventy-six yard pass to Reggie Baul and --
并且一次都没被擒杀过
and never sacked once.
你记性真好
You have got quite a memory.
算是吧  这么说吧
Yeah, well, uh, I'll tell you what.
我到现在都还清楚记得
I can remember every stitch of clothing
看那场球赛时我穿的什么衣服
I was wearing during that game,
但你要问我昨晚吃了什么
but ask me what I had for dinner last night
一片空白
and clean slate.
可不是嘛
Yeah. Tell me about it.
跟你说  要是不传球的话
Well, I tell ya, if you're not passing the ball,
就会变成那样
that's what's gonna happen.
十八  凯特·丝蓓女王范
Eighteen, Kate Spade's queen.
十九  凯文克莱皮衣眼前摆
Nineteen, Calvin leathers on the scene.
二十  UGG雪地靴真滑稽
Twenty, Uggs look funny.
画面很好看  收割者队的红球衣搭配绿草地
Sure looks pretty, Huskers red against that green.
就像在过圣诞节一样
It's like Christmas out there.
你没事吧
You okay?
呛着了
Wrong pipe.
好吧
Oh. Oh, okay.
你觉得咱们球队会像他们说的那样
So, you think our guys are gonna move to the Big Ten
进大十联盟吗
like they're saying?
大十联盟
Big Ten?
对  依我看他们只是
Yeah. I mean, they're just chasing
一心向钱看啦
the, you know, mighty dollar, if you ask me.
当然了  两边都很强
I mean, both powerhouses, 'course.
不过  这里有俄克拉荷马和得克萨斯
But, you know, you got Oklahoma and Texas over here.
而那边有密歇根和俄亥俄
But Michigan, Ohio State over there.
不好说
I-I don't know.
我可能还是比较喜欢传统
Guess I like tradition.
太好吃了
So good.
这个芯
That center.
太美味了
Just amazing.
天啊
Oh, God.
我在干什么啊
What am I doing?
怎么了
What?
看着我  我不知道
Look at me! I don't know.
我不知道
I-I don't know.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
吉恩
Gene?
我的老天
Oh, God.
你...
You...
你有老婆了  对吗  弗兰克
You have a wife, right, Frank?
-是  -对吧
- Well, yeah. - Yeah?
她在家等着你
And she's waiting for you.
看看我
Look at me.
我...
I got...
孤家寡人一个
I got no one.
我父母死了
My parents are dead.
我哥哥...
My brother...
我哥哥也死了
My brother is dead.
我...
I, uh...
没有老婆
I got no wife...
没有孩子
No kids.
没有朋友
No friends.
就算我今晚死了
If I died tonight...
也不会有人在意
no one would care.
死不死又有什么差别呢
What difference would it make?
吉恩  好兄弟
Gene, buddy...
不是的  我相信你对很多人来说
No, I-I-I'm sure that you mean a lot to, you know --
都是很重要的存在
to a lot of -- lots of people.
如果我今晚死了  我房东会帮我收拾东西
If I died tonight, my landlord would pack up my stuff.
就占用他三个小时
It'd take him three hours.
而辛纳邦也会雇个新店长
And Cinnabon would just hire a new manager.
吉恩是哪位
Gene who?
嗖的一下
Poof!
我就消失不见了  我会变成...
I'd be gone. I'd be...
一个
a...
一个鬼魂
a ghost.
鬼魂都算不上  我会变成一个影子
Less than a ghost. I'd be a -- a sha-- shadow.
我...
I'd just be...
什么都不是
nothing.
弗兰克  这有什么意义呢  弗兰克
I mean, Frank -- what's the point, Frank?
意义何在
What's the poi--
对不起
Oh, you -- I'm so sorry.
让你听我发牢骚了
You didn't need to hear any of that.
不不不  没事的
No, no, no, no, no, that's -- that's okay.
没关系的
No, that -- that is okay.
谁都有不开心的时候
Everybody has bad days.
你有过这种感觉吗
You've felt like this?
我倒没有  但总有人有
No, I mean, not me -- but people.
很多人都会有这种感觉的
I-I think a lot of people.
就像人生总是起起伏伏的
Yeah, I mean, I-it's just like life's ups and life's downs.
是啊
Yeah.
你不会跟尼克说的吧
Hey, you're not gonna tell Nick, are you?
当然不会
No, 'course not.
谢谢你听我倒苦水
Well...thanks so much for listening.
当然  小事情
Yeah, no, no. No p-- No problem.
我不确定
I don't know.
蓝色或者黑色吧
I'm thinking maybe blue or black?
是什么场合
What's the occasion?
我姐妹的婚礼
My sister's wedding.
真好
Oh, very exciting.
您穿什么尺码的
Um, what size are you?
一般是38或者40的
Usually a 38 or a 40?
两件都试试怎么样
Do you want to try both?
好啊
Yeah. Let's do it.
先生  有什么需要吗
Sir, do you need help?
不用
I'm good.
您有事找那边的芭芭拉就行
Well, Barbara's right here if you need anything.
-凯茜  是这件吗  -是的
- Kathy, is this it? - Yes.
打扰了女士  取大箱子的货车到了
Excuse me, ma'am? Truck's here to pick up that big box.
太好了  谢谢
Great, thank you.
那个人还送了花
Uh... the guy brought flowers.
真的吗
Really?
-快看  -美得很
- Look. - Ooh la la! Ooh la la!
瞧这件
Check this out.
女士们早啊
Buongiorno, ladies!
你觉得这些能卖多少钱
How much you think we can get for 'em?
不知道  每件大概五百块吧
I don't know. Maybe...five hundred each?
但说真的
But shit, man.
我干脆留着自己穿好了
Maybe I just keep 'em for myself.
我眼馋这几双球鞋很久了
I've been eyeing these Jordans.
你们很爽吧
You guys enjoying yourselves?
那就记住这种感觉
Well, hold onto that feeling.
因为到此为止了
'Cause this is it.
我们知道
Yeah, we know.
怕你们忘了
Well, in case you forget...
你们转运了
You transported stolen goods
价格超过五千美元的赃物
with a value exceeding five thousand dollars.
你们开的货车是从州界旁的康瑟尔布拉夫斯市
And the truck you used to do it was rented in Council Bluffs,
租用的
across state lines.
是你叫我们在那里租的
You told us to rent the truck over there --
州际运输失窃
Theft from an Interstate Shipment.
最多能判十年
Up to ten years.
转运赃物  又判十年
Transportation of Stolen Goods. Another ten years.
销售赃物  再加十年
Sale of Stolen Goods. Ten years.
合谋犯下联邦罪行
Conspiracy to commit a federal crime --
合谋  这是你的主意好吗
"Conspiracy"? It was your idea.
是没错  这叫"相互保证毁灭"
Yeah. It's called "Mutually assured destruction."
我要是出事了  也会拉着你们同归于尽
So, if I go down, you go down.
你不用威胁我们的
Man, you don't have to threaten us.
大家都是朋友一场
We're all friends here.
我不是你们的朋友
I am not your friend.
你们要是掉钱眼里了  还想回来再干一票
And if you get greedy and you decide
我劝你打消这个念头
to come back for more, don't.
吉恩·塔卡维奇  你们从没听说过这个人
Gene Takavic -- you never heard of him.
棉白杨商场  你们再也别去
The Cottonwood Mall? You don't go there.
路上见到我了  就过个马路绕着我走
You see me coming, you cross to the other side of the street.
老兄
Dude --
都照着我的说  "我们洗手不干了"
Now I need you to say it: "We're done."
-干啥呢  -快说
- Come on! - Say it.
"我们洗手不干了"
"We're. Done."
说
Say it.
我们洗手不干了
We're done.
我们...洗手不干了
We're -- We're done.
吉恩
Gene?
吉恩  我看见你的车了
Hey, Gene, I see your car!
吉恩
Gene?
总之开了个头
Well, that's a start.
看起来问题出在制动主缸
Looks like your problem is the master cylinder.
瞧瞧你们  正在卖力干活呢
Look at you boys, hard at work.
玛丽恩  两位  我得走了
Well, Marion, guys, I got to get going.
我下次来了再帮你看看
I will take another look next time.
等会儿
Wait a minute.
你一身脏兮兮的能去哪呢
No, you can't go anywhere looking like that.
快进屋里洗洗
Come on inside and wash up.
妈
Ma...
杰夫  别烦我  快点  吉恩
Jeffie, don't vex me. Come on, Gene.
你可以帮我放杂货
You can help me with the groceries.
-吉恩  -听起来不错
- Huh, Gene? - Sounds like a plan.
你帮杰夫修车真好
Nice of you to help Jeffie with his car.
你也许不知道  我儿子以前过得不太顺
You might not know it, but my boy's had some tough times.
他在阿尔布开克摊上了一群坏人
He, uh -- He fell in with a bad crowd back in Albuquerque.
阿尔布开克  我没去过
Albuquerque, huh? Never been.
你真走运
Lucky you.
但杰夫在这里就好多了
But things are so much better for Jeffie here.
如今认识了你那是好上加好
Even more so now that he knows you.
你能给他带来好的影响  吉恩
You're a good influence, Gene.
你瞧我这脑子
Oh, where's my brain?
我一直忘了问你咬咬的事
I keep forgetting to ask you about Nippy.
咬咬
Nippy?
是哦
Oh, oh, right.
你肯定不会相信的
You're not gonna believe this,
它其实一直
but, uh, he was with a family
都待在一户人家里  离这就几个街区
the whole time, just -- just a few blocks away.
那真是太棒了
Oh, well, that's wonderful!
嗯  它好得很
Yeah. He's in great shape.
折腾了这么久
So, after all that...
还好有个圆满结局
a happy ending.
真是
Oh, well...
-给您  女士  -谢谢
- Here you go, Ma'am. - Thanks.
稍等
And looky here.
-给您  小姐  -谢谢你
- For you, m'lady. - Thank you.
吉恩  你不吃午饭吗
Hey, Gene, aren't you taking lunch?
谢了
Thanks.
我懂  你就挺过去吧  好吗
I get it. You get over it, okay?
请你相信我
Please, believe me.
你不知不觉中就会忘掉这一切的
Before you know it, you'll forget all about it.
去吧
Go.